Guide to the Sylvester Manor Archive 1649-1996 MSS.208
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Record Group II: L'Hommedieu Family
  - Series B: Ezra L'Hommedieu
    - Subseries 7: New York State Government Documents and Reports
      - "Act Concerning Ownership of Property Laws in NY", undated; cuid748 (Box 24, Folder 28)
      - Report - Committee, Governor Clinton's Letters, circa 1880s; cuid749 (Box 24, Folder 29)
        This item was removed from Horsford Genealogy Notes circa 1886 in Box 110, Folder 4.
    - Subseries 8: Upstate New York Land Materials
      - "Old Bills, Powers of Attorney & Deeds" [1 of 3], 1757 - 1763; cuid750 (Box 25, Folder 1)
      - "Old Bills, Powers of Attorney & Deeds" [2 of 3], 1760 - 1765; cuid751 (Box 25, Folder 2)
      - "Old Bills, Powers of Attorney & Deeds" [3 of 3], 1760 - 1767; cuid752 (Box 25, Folder 3)
      - Articles of Agreement - James Cory, Montgomery County, 1791 October 27; cuid753 (Box 25, Folder 4)
      - "Tryon County, Canadaraho Lake, Whitestown", 1784 - 1792; cuid754 (Box 25, Folder 5)
      - "Chenango, Randolph, Whitestown, North Platt", 1782 - 1794; cuid755 (Box 25, Folder 6)
      - "Seneca Lake Area", 1784 - 1797; cuid756 (Box 25, Folder 7)
      - "Seneca Lake, Whitestone, Plattsburgh", 1788 - 1794; cuid757 (Box 25, Folder 8)
      - Indenture - Township 12, William Constable, 1797 January 17; cuid758 (Box 25, Folder 9)
      - Agreement - Township 12, John Smith, Zacheus Goldsmith, 1797 March 29; cuid759 (Box 25, Folder 10)
      - "Herkemer & Oneida Counties; Salmon River, Mexico, Township 12", 1797 - 1798; cuid760 (Box 25, Folder 11)
      - "50% Reduction on Unsettled Lands", 1800 August 16; cuid761 (Box 25, Folder 12)
      - "Salmon River, Township 12", 1796 - 1800; cuid762 (Box 25, Folder 13)
      - "Redfield Prospectus", 1801 February; cuid763 (Box 25, Folder 14)
      - Taxes - Redfield, Brookfield, Mexico, Plattsburgh & Peru, 1801 September 26; cuid764 (Box 25, Folder 15)
      - Receipts - Taxes, Redfield County, 1801 October 10; cuid765 (Box 25, Folder 16)
      - Receipt - Real Estate Taxes, 1801 October 21; cuid766 (Box 25, Folder 17)
      - Appointment - Benjamin Wright, Office of Surveyor of the Revenue, 1801 December 25; cuid767 (Box 25, Folder 18)
      - "Salmon River, Township 12, Montgomery County", 1796 - 1801; cuid768 (Box 25, Folder 19)
      - "Twenty Townships, Redfield, Township 12, Mexico", 1798 - 1801; cuid769 (Box 25, Folder 20)
      - "Redfield", 1800 - 1801; cuid770 (Box 25, Folder 21)
      - Petition - Redfield Taxes, 1802 January 29; cuid771 (Box 25, Folder 22)
      - Receipt - Taxes, Chenango, 1802 March 23; cuid772 (Box 25, Folder 23)
      - Receipt - Taxes, Redfield, 1802 April 6; cuid773 (Box 25, Folder 24)
      - Assorted Professional Correspondence, 1802; cuid774 (Box 25, Folder 25)
      - Payment Vouchers - Salmon River, 1796 - 1802; cuid775 (Box 25, Folder 26)
      - Financial Records - Real Estate Taxes, 1802 - 1803; cuid776 (Box 25, Folder 27)
      - "Construction of Grist Mill in Township 12"; Taxes - Redfield, 1797 - 1798, 1803; cuid777 (Box 25, Folder 28)
      - Receipt - Property Taxes, 1804 November 6; cuid778 (Box 25, Folder 29)
      - Taxes, 1803 - 1804; cuid779 (Box 25, Folder 30)
      - Taxes - Real Estate, 1803 - 1804; cuid780 (Box 25, Folder 31)
      - "Redfield, Halimony Rivers", 1797 - 1804; cuid781 (Box 25, Folder 32)
      - "Seneca, Oneida, [Chemmy, Colhosine]", 1789 - 1804; cuid782 (Box 25, Folder 33)
      - "Township 12, Mexico", 1801, 1804; cuid783 (Box 25, Folder 34)
      - Taxes - Real Estate, 1804 - 1805; cuid784 (Box 26, Folder 1)
      - "Seneca Lake, Three Rivers, Onandaga", 1791 - 1805; cuid785 (Box 26, Folder 2)
      - "Seneca Lake Area", 1792 - 1805; cuid786 (Box 26, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence - Steuben, Joseph Montague & John Gardiner, 1794 - 1805; cuid787 (Box 26, Folder 4)
      - Account Book - Salmon River, 1796-1805; cuid788 (Box 26, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence & Contracts - Steuben Land, Joseph Montague, Benjamin Wright, 1800 - 1805; cuid789 (Box 26, Folder 6)
      - "Oneida County, Mexico, Redfield, Camden", 1806; cuid790 (Box 26, Folder 7)
      - Correspondence - Steuben Land, Joseph Montague, Benjamin Wright, 1796 - 1806; cuid791 (Box 26, Folder 8)
      - "Herkimer County, Jersey Field, Lawrence Patent, Whitetown, Montgomery County", 1782 - 1807; cuid792 (Box 26, Folder 9)
      - "Tioga County, Randolph", 1791-1794, 1807; cuid793 (Box 26, Folder 10)
      - Account Book - Salmon River, 1796 - 1807; cuid794 (Box 26, Folder 11)
      - "Redfield, Mexico, Township 12, Oneida County", 1797 - 1798, 1806 - 1807; cuid795 (Box 26, Folder 12)
      - "Redfield", 1803-1807; cuid796 (Box 26, Folder 13)
      - "Twenty Townships", circa 1795-1809; cuid797 (Box 27, Folder 1)
      - "Mexico", 1797, 1809; cuid798 (Box 27, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence, Certificate, Memorandum - Plattsburgh, Henry Delord, 1786 - 1810; cuid799 (Box 27, Folder 3)
      - "Herkimer and Montgomery Counties, Danube, Minden & Canajoharie", 1793 - 1810; cuid800 (Box 27, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence - Plattsburgh, Joseph Bourn, Seth Sherry, Henry Delord, 1805 - 1810; cuid801 (Box 27, Folder 5)
      - "Broome County, Randolph", 1789, 1794, 1807 - 1811; cuid802 (Box 27, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence - Steuben, Joseph Montague, John L. Gardiner, Jacob Crams, 1790 - 1811; cuid803 (Box 27, Folder 7)
      - "Lands near Plattsburgh, Bourn, Cochran, Delord", 1804-1811; cuid804 (Box 27, Folder 8)
      - "Chemung, Mohawk River", 1786, 1789-1790, 1799, 1812; cuid805 (Box 27, Folder 9)
      - "Broome County, Chenango", 1791, 1807-1812; cuid806 (Box 27, Folder 10)
      - "Brookfield, Sangerfield", 1806-1807, 1810-1813; cuid807 (Box 27, Folder 11)
      - Notes & Receipts - Redfield, 1800 - 1809, 1813; cuid808 (Box 27, Folder 12)
      - "Redfield, Oswago River, [Thichland]", 1795 - 1814; cuid809 (Box 27, Folder 13)
      - "Upstate New York", 1807, 1810-1811, 1817, undated; cuid810 (Box 27, Folder 14)
      - Contract - Sylvester Dering & Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu, Stephen Brook, Redfield, 1819; cuid811 (Box 27, Folder 15)
      - Upstate New York Lands: Redfield, 1774, 1791, 1802, 1812-1813, 1818-1819; cuid5738; 1 folder (Box 27, Folder 16)
      - "Steuben, 20 Townships", 1800 - 1819; cuid812 (Box 27, Folder 17)
      - "Twenty Townships," with Southold Deed, [Copy, Original 1712], circa 1807-1819; cuid813 (Box 27, Folder 18)
      - "Twenty Townships", circa 1797-1820; cuid814 (Box 27, Folder 19)
      - "Montgomery County, South of Mohawk River, John Taylor", 1784, 1789, 1810-1811, 1824; cuid815 (Box 28, Folder 1)
      - "Plattsburgh, Lake Champlain, Clinton County, Peru", 1789 - 1824; cuid816 (Box 28, Folder 2)
      - Bonds, Contracts & Mortgages - Redfield, 1800-1808, 1819-1824; cuid817 (Box 28, Folder 3)
      - "Windsor County, Randolph", 1807-1825; cuid818 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - "Randolph, Windsor", 1811-1825; cuid819 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - Account Book - Redfield, circa 1828; cuid820 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Receipts & Accounts - NY Upstate Taxes, 1806-1829; cuid821 (Box 28, Folder 7)
      - Taxes - Redfield, 1809, 1820-1827, 1830; cuid822 (Box 28, Folder 8)
      - Power of Attorney of Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu to Samuel Gardiner; Taxes - Redfield, 1824, 1830, undated; cuid823 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - "Chenango, Redfield, Brookfield, Windsor, Rome, Black River", 1791 - 1806, 1832; cuid824 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - Taxes - Redfield, undated; cuid825 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - "Remarks made on the lots in Township no. 12 on Salmon River", undated; cuid826 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - "Committee on Petition for Relief from Taxes", undated; cuid827 (Box 28, Folder 13)
      - "Proprietors of Redfield Unsold Acres", undated; cuid828 (Box 28, Folder 14)
      - "Salmon River Map" & Property Description Notes, circa 1809; cuid829 (Box 28, Folder 15)
      - Webb, Booth & Corey Property Description Notes, undated; cuid830 (Box 28, Folder 17)
    - Subseries 9: Personal Papers and Poetry
      - Recipes & Formulas - Culinary & Medicinal, undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid831 (Box 28, Folder 18)
      - Letter Wrappers [Loose, Unused], undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid832 (Box 28, Folder 19)
      - Letter Wrapper - "Letters 1795", undated, circa 1795; cuid833 (Box 28, Folder 20)
      - Poem - "Queen Elizabeth Lammantation", undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid834 (Box 28, Folder 21)
      - Poem - Untitled, undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid835 (Box 28, Folder 22)
      - Agricultural Papers & Notes, 1797 - 1804; cuid836 (Box 28, Folder 23)
      - List - NY Towns & Counties, 1790; cuid837 (Box 28, Folder 24)
      - Design - Ezra L'Hommedieu Memorial, undated, circa 1800s; cuid838 (Box 28, Folder 25)
      - Tombstone Inscription - [Chastity L'Hommedieu, Copy], 1785; cuid839 (Box 28, Folder 26)
      - Invitations & Card - "Turkey Work Wallet", undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid840 (Box 28, Folder 27)
      - Poem - "Vigor A talis fluit ut Flos Voris" by Nicoll Havens, undated, circa 1750 - 1811; cuid841 (Box 28, Folder 28)
      - Poem - Untitled by Robert Burns, 1786; cuid842 (Box 28, Folder 29)
      - "A Chart of the Port of Sag Harbor", circa 1800; cuid843 (Box 28, Folder 30)
  - Series C: Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu
    Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu was born to Nicoll Havens and Sarah Fosdick of Shelter Island, NY on September 25, 1765. Mary Catherine wed Ezra L'Hommedieu of Southold, Long Island, NY on June 15, 1803. This was Ezra L'Hommedieu's second marriage and they produced one daughter, Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu, born in 1806. Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu's sister Esther Sarah married Sylvester Dering, the son of Thomas Dering, also of Shelter Island. Ezra L'Hommedieu left his estate, which included Sylvester Manor, to Mary Catherine Havens when he passed away on September 27, 1811, and it was later inherited by their daughter Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu Gardiner and her husband Samuel Smith Gardiner. Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu passed away in 1843.
    Record Group II, Series C includes personal correspondence primarily among relatives and close family friends of Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu. In addition, Series C includes Ezra L'Hommedieu estate management records, legal documents, and financial papers.
    - Subseries 1: Correspondence
      - Barnes, D.H. to Charles Thomas Dering, 1822; cuid844 (Box 28, Folder 31)
      - "Cousin," [Unidentified], 1820 - 1823; cuid845 (Box 28, Folder 32)
      - Dering, Anna, 1808, 1824; cuid846 (Box 28, Folder 33)
      - Dering, Anna & Frances, 1823; cuid847 (Box 28, Folder 34)
      - Dering, Charles Thomas, 1821-1824; cuid848 (Box 28, Folder 35)
      - Dering, Charles Thomas, 1824; cuid849 (Box 28, Folder 36)
      - Dering, Henry P., 1814; cuid850 (Box 28, Folder 37)
      - Dering, Henry P., 1816 January 2; cuid851 (Box 28, Folder 38)
        Enclosed with letter Frank S. Landers to Andrew Fiske 1963, Box 118 Folder 12.
      - Dering, Nicoll H., 1822, 1837; cuid852 (Box 28, Folder 39)
      - Dering, Sarah F., 1819; cuid853 (Box 29, Folder 1)
      - Franklin, S.D. to Sarah Dering, 1821 January 21; cuid854 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Havens, Renslieur, 1811; cuid855 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Huntington, Catherine M., 1831; cuid856 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - L'Hommedieu, Ezra, 1804; cuid857 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Lynch, Anne C., 1832; cuid858 (Box 29, Folder 6)
      - Skinner, Gloriana, 1788; cuid859 (Box 29, Folder 7)
      - Taylor, John, undated, circa 1800 - 1843; cuid860 (Box 29, Folder 8)
    - Subseries 2: Legal and Financial Materials
      - Promissory Note - Lazarus Cleveland, Thomas Lester, Sylvester Dering, 1812; cuid861 (Box 29, Folder 9)
      - Memorandum - Ezra L'Hommedieu Clothing, 1813; cuid862 (Box 29, Folder 10)
      - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1813 - 1814; cuid863 (Box 29, Folder 11)
      - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1813 - 1815; cuid864 (Box 29, Folder 12)
      - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1814 - 1815; cuid865 (Box 29, Folder 13)
      - Accounts, Bills, Receipts, 1816 - 1818; cuid866 (Box 29, Folder 14)
      - Power of Attorney - Sylvester Dering, 1818; cuid867 (Box 29, Folder 15)
      - Inventory - Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu Books, 1818; cuid868 (Box 29, Folder 16)
      - Memorandum - Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu Articles, 1818; cuid869 (Box 29, Folder 17)
      - Inventory - Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu's Silver & Gold to Sylvester Dering, 1820; cuid870 (Box 29, Folder 18)
      - Report of the Board of Directors of the Presbyterian Education Society, 1820; cuid871 (Box 29, Folder 19)
      - Account Book, 1812 - 1820; cuid872 (Box 29, Folder 20)
      - Account & Memorandum Book, 1818 - 1821; cuid873 (Box 29, Folder 21)
      - "A Catechism of Scripture Doctrine", 1820; cuid874 (Box 29, Folder 22)
      - American Missionary Register, 1823 October; cuid875 (Box 29, Folder 23)
      - Account & Memorandum Book - "Inventory of Great Many Events", 1818 - 1827; cuid876 (Box 29, Folder 24)
      - Genealogy Notes, 1828; cuid877 (Box 29, Folder 25)
      - Account & Memorandum Book, 1820 - 1832; cuid878 (Box 29, Folder 26)
      - Account & Memorandum Book, 1824 - 1834; cuid879 (Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Account & Memorandum Book, 1831 - 1838; cuid880 (Box 30, Folder 2)
      - Memorandum, 1839 January 15; cuid881 (Box 30, Folder 3)
      - Biils, Memoranda, Notes, Receipts, 1808 - 1842; cuid882 (Box 30, Folder 4)
      - Note - Gold Eagle, Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu Gardiner, 1842; cuid883 (Box 30, Folder 5)
      - Genealogy Notes, undated, circa 1800 - 1843; cuid884 (Box 30, Folder 6)
      - Pamphlet - "The Criminal Court", undated, circa 1800s; cuid885 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Series D: Sylvester Dering
    Sylvester Dering was born in 1758 to Boston politician Thomas Dering (circa 1716 - 1785) and daughter of Brinley Sylvester, Mary Sylvester. During his lifetime, Sylvester Dering owned and managed Sylvester Manor, in addition to earning the rank of General during the American Revolutionary War. Dering was a brigadier in the Rhode Island state militia and saw action at the Battle of Oriskany in central NY. Sylvester Dering was also a member of the State Assembly for Suffolk County from 1803 - 1804, and became the first vice-president of the Suffolk County Agricultural Society in 1818. Sylvester Dering married Esther Sarah Havens, sister to Mary Catherine Havens L'Hommedieu, wife of Ezra L'Hommedieu; he was appointed as one of the executors of Ezra L'Hommedieu's estate and passed away in 1820. The Dering Family Papers (1755 - 1896) are housed at the William L. Clements Library of the University of Michigan at Ann Arbor, MI.
    Record Group II, Series D includes legal, personal, and professional correspondence in past possession of Sylvester Dering, but pertaining to the manangement of Ezra L'Hommedieu's estate.
    - Bradford, LeBaron, 1819 - 1820; cuid886 (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - Briggs, William R., 1819; cuid887 (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Case, Ebenezer W., 1818; cuid888 (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Clark, Aaron, 1818 - 1820; cuid889 (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Havens, Jonathan, 1795; cuid890 (Box 30, Folder 12)
    - Horner, John, 1819; cuid891 (Box 30, Folder 13)
    - Jackson, Samuel, 1818; cuid892 (Box 30, Folder 14)
    - Ledyard, Thomas, 1814 April 1; cuid893 (Box 30, Folder 15)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1799, 1800, 1803; cuid894 (Box 30, Folder 16)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1814 - 1815; cuid895 (Box 30, Folder 17)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1815 - 1818; cuid896 (Box 30, Folder 18)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1819 - 1820; cuid897 (Box 30, Folder 19)
    - Morton, Ichabod, 1819 - 1820; cuid898 (Box 30, Folder 20)
    - Skiff, Ebenezer, 1820 August 9; cuid899 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Series E: Thomas Lester
    Southold, Long Island, NY attorney and politian Thomas Lester was appointed in Ezra L’Hommedieu’s will as one of the executors of his estate.
    Record Group II, Series E includes legal and professional correspondence pertaining to the management of Ezra L'Hommedieu's estate after his death.
    - Bigg, Samuel, 1812 January 28; cuid900 (Box 30, Folder 22)
    - Bourne, Nathaniel, 1819 December 24; cuid901 (Box 30, Folder 23)
    - Bradford, Lebaron, 1819; cuid902 (Box 30, Folder 24)
    - Brown, Daniel, 1812; cuid903 (Box 30, Folder 25)
    - Burrows, Latham, 1811 March 10; cuid904 (Box 30, Folder 26)
    - Conkling, Nathaniel, 1814; cuid905 (Box 30, Folder 27)
    - Crook, Victor, 1812 April 5; cuid906 (Box 30, Folder 28)
    - Davis, David, 1812 October 12; cuid907 (Box 30, Folder 29)
    - Dering, Charles Thomas, 1813 - 1817; cuid908 (Box 30, Folder 30)
    - Dering, Henry Parker, 1805, 1815; cuid909 (Box 30, Folder 31)
    - Dering, Sylvester, 1805, 1812 - 1816; cuid910 (Box 30, Folder 32)
    - Franks, John, 1811; cuid911 (Box 30, Folder 33)
    - Gardiner, John, 1812; cuid912 (Box 30, Folder 34)
    - Gardiner, Mary Catherine L'Hommedieu, 1812, 1814; cuid913 (Box 30, Folder 35)
    - Gardiner, Robert Smith, 1811 December 12; cuid914 (Box 30, Folder 36)
    - Gleston, H., 1812; cuid915 (Box 30, Folder 37)
    - Griffin, Augustus, 1812 October 31; cuid916 (Box 30, Folder 38)
    - Hart, Mo E., 1812 December 12; cuid917 (Box 30, Folder 39)
    - Havens, Charles H., 1812; cuid918 (Box 30, Folder 40)
    - Havens, Gabriel, 1812 December 16; cuid919 (Box 31, Folder 1)
    - Havens, Rensselaer, 1813 - 1814; cuid920 (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Hedges, Jesse, 1812 November 11; cuid921 (Box 31, Folder 3)
    - Hempsted, David, 1812 June 18; cuid922 (Box 31, Folder 4)
    - Howell, S., 1812 August 13; cuid923 (Box 31, Folder 5)
    - Hudson, Richard to Thomas Lester, 1812 January 3; cuid924 (Box 31, Folder 6)
    - Ingraham, John, 1812; cuid925 (Box 31, Folder 7)
    - Ingraham, Nathaniel, 1813 - 1817; cuid926 (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - Isaacs, John, 1811 December 25; cuid927 (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - Jones, Abel, 1815; cuid928 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - King, Frederick, 1812; cuid929 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - L'Hommedieu, Ezra, 1807, 1811; cuid930 (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1813; cuid931 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1813 - 1814; cuid932 (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1814; cuid933 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1814 - 1815; cuid934 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - L'Hommedieu, Mary Catherine Havens, 1815 - 1816; cuid935 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - L'Hommedieu, Samuel, 1811 - 1815; cuid936 (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Moore, H.M., 1812 May 31; cuid937 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Morton, Ichabod, 1819 February 11; cuid938 (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Mulford, Elisha, 1812 October 24; cuid939 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Osborn, Wines, 1812 October 27; cuid940 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Overton, Silvanus, 1812 February 11; cuid941 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Post, Joel and Jonathan, 1812 January 14; cuid942 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Prince, Nehemiah B., 1812 May 25; cuid943 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Reeve, Joanna and James Hendrickson, 1812 January 30; cuid944 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Reeve, Josiah, 1812 February 1; cuid945 (Box 31, Folder 27)
    - Romaine, Samuel B., 1811 - 1812; cuid946 (Box 31, Folder 28)
    - Russell, Matthew T., 1813; cuid947 (Box 31, Folder 29)
    - Ryder, Enoch, 1812; cuid948 (Box 31, Folder 30)
    - Sage, E., 1811 - 1812; cuid949 (Box 31, Folder 31)
    - Sage, E., 1812; cuid950 (Box 31, Folder 32)
    - Sage, E., 1812; cuid951 (Box 31, Folder 33)
    - Sanford, Nathaniel, 1812; cuid952 (Box 31, Folder 34)
    - Satterly, Issac, 1812 September 5; cuid953 (Box 31, Folder 35)
    - Schermerhor, Peter & Sons, 1812 June 22; cuid954 (Box 31, Folder 36)
    - Scott, John to Thomas Lester, 1812 August 19; cuid955 (Box 31, Folder 37)
    - Skinner, Abraham, 1811 - 1812; cuid956 (Box 31, Folder 38)
    - Sleight, Cornelius, 1812; cuid957 (Box 31, Folder 39)
    - Smiths, David, 1812 February 12; cuid958 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Smith, General John, 1812 February - May; cuid959 (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Smith, General John, 1812 June - December; cuid960 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Spooner, A., 1812 September 7; cuid961 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Stors, Jared, 1812 December 18; cuid962 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Stors, John, 1814 - 1816; cuid963 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Strong, George W., 1813; cuid964 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Terry, Joseph, 1812; cuid965 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Thompson, Benjamin F., 1811 - 1813; cuid966 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Topping, S., undated, circa early 1800s; cuid967 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Tucker, Benjamin, 1813; cuid968 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Tuthill, Rufus, 1812; cuid969 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Udal, William, 1812; cuid970 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Webb, David, 1812 October 3; cuid971 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Wickes, E., 1812; cuid972 (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Wright, Benjamin, 1814 August 7; cuid973 (Box 32, Folder 16)
  - L'Hommedieu: Oversize
    - Oversize Series A, Subseries 1: Benjamin L'Hommedieu
      - Deed - Thomas Youngs, Benjamin L'Hommedieu, Sr., Southold, 1709; cuid974 (Box 142, Folder 12)
      - Contract - Benjamin L'Hommedieu, Sr. & Benjamin L'Hommedieu, Jr., Orchard, 1727; cuid975 (Box 142, Folder 13)
      - Transfer of Land - Thomas Conkling, Mary Conkling, 1732; cuid976 (Box 142, Folder 14)
      - Indenture - John L'Hommedieu, James Atkins for "Negro Fellow Named Jo", 1737; cuid977 (Box 142, Folder 15)
      - Account - Jon & Jonathan Simpson, 1752; cuid978 (Box 142, Folder 16)
    - Oversize Series B, Subseries 1: Ezra L'Hommedieu Correspondence
      - Bigelow, Timothy H., 1789; cuid979 (Box 142, Folder 17)
      - Bourn, Benjamin, 1801; cuid980 (Box 142, Folder 18)
      - Bourn, Nathaniel, 1806; cuid981 (Box 142, Folder 19)
      - Broome, Samuel, 1763 - 1764; cuid982 (Box 142, Folder 20)
      - Clinton, DeWitt, 1810; cuid983 (Box 142, Folder 21)
      - Clinton, George, 1783; cuid984 (Box 142, Folder 22)
      - Daggett, T., 1791; cuid985 (Box 142, Folder 23)
      - Fanning, P., 1784; cuid986 (Box 142, Folder 24)
      - Fish, Nicholas [Adjutant General to Colonel Phineas Fanning], 1786; cuid987 (Box 142, Folder 25)
      - Floyd, William, 1783; cuid988 (Box 142, Folder 26)
      - Gelston, David, 1780, 1783, 1790, 1804; cuid989 (Box 142, Folder 27)
      - Havens, Jonathan N., 1792, 1796; cuid990 (Box 142, Folder 28)
      - Hilhouse, James A., 1763; cuid991 (Box 142, Folder 29)
      - to Jefferson, Thomas: "Resolutions of the Society for the Promotion of Agriculture, Arts & Manufactures", 1802; cuid992 (Box 142, Folder 30)
      - Lamb, John with Maximus Willett & Hugh Hughes, 1784; cuid993 (Box 142, Folder 31)
      - Livingston, James, 1784; cuid994 (Box 142, Folder 32)
      - Livingston, P.V.B., 1784; cuid995 (Box 142, Folder 33)
      - Livingston, William, 1764; cuid996 (Box 142, Folder 34)
      - Morse, Jedediah: Gazeteer of North America, 1788; cuid997 (Box 142, Folder 35)
      - Pool, Simon, 1792; cuid998 (Box 142, Folder 36)
      - Potter, Gilbert, undated, circa 1780 - 1810; cuid999 (Box 147, Folder 37)
      - Smith, Elihu Hubbard, 1792; cuid1000 (Box 147, Folder 38)
      - Smith, George, 1792; cuid1001 (Box 142, Folder 37)
      - Thompson, Benjamin F., 1810; cuid1002 (Box 142, Folder 38)
      - Troup, Robert: "About Negroes Imported with Settlers", 1803; cuid1003 (Box 142, Folder 39)
      - Vaill, James to Benjamin Vaill, 1810; cuid1004 (Box 142, Folder 40)
      - Walker, Benjamin, 1792 May 25; cuid1005 (Box 142, Folder 42)
      - Whitefield, George to Thomas Dering, 1764; cuid1006 (Box 142, Folder 41)
    - Oversize Series B, Subseries 2: Ezra L'Hommedieu Financial Documents and Papers
      - Accounts & Receipts - James McClure, 1755 - 1779; cuid1007 (Box 143, Folder 1)